Guide to Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union Local 12 Records, 1945-1996 AIS.1997.13
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union Local 12 Records
1945-1996
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 12 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1997.13
2.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 12 represents workers at commercial bakeries in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. This collection includes meeting minutes and NLRB case reports of Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers' International Union Locals 12 and 12-A.
Previous Citation
Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union Local 12 Records, 1945-1997, AIS.1997.13, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sam Papa in May 1997.
History
Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 12 represents workers at commercial bakeries in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Excessive wildcat strikes and factionalism within the local led to the national union placing Local 12 under trusteeship of their International Vice President before the AFL-CIO expelled the entire union due to corrupt practices in 1957. In 1958, the newly formed American Bakery and Confectionery Workers Union of the AFL-CIO won collective bargaining rights from the former union and the two unions merged in 1969. In 1991, when Braun Bakery closed its doors after 100 years in Pittsburgh, members of Local 12, with help from the Steel Valley Authority, were able to raise enough funds to create the partially employee-owned City Pride Bakery in Lawrenceville. The bakery closed in 1994.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection includes meeting minutes of Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers' International Union Locals 12 and 12-A. Much of the minutes include both original and photocopied versions. Also included are National Labor Relations Board case reports regarding the local, as well as bakery union Pennsylvania state conference proceedings.
Related Material
Bakery and Confectionery International Union Local 44 Records, 1917-1937, AIS.1978.21, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Bakery Drivers' Union, Teamsters Local 485 Records, 1954-1969, AIS.1997.07, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Correspondence; Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor disputes -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Minutes (Administrative records); Confectioners -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Bakery employees -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Bakery employees -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Proceedings (Reports); Decisions; Labor; Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America. Local 12 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 12 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); American Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union. Local 12 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); United States. National Labor Relations Board
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1949-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
- Bakery, Confectionery & Tobacco Workers International Union 100 Years Souvenir Program, May 10, 1986 (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Meeting Minutes, 1948-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1-49)
- "Beware and Behold" Union Label Bread Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Anthony Guadagnino and Vincent Mero Investigation, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- American Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union, Local 12 v. National Biscut Co., Cracker Division, May 5-9, 1958 (Box 2, Volume 1-5)
- American Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union, Local 12 v. Clark Brothers Chewing Gum Co., August 4, 1958 (Box 2, Volume 6)
- American Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union, Local 12 v. D.L. Clark Co., September 2, 1958 (Box 2, Volume 7)
- Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union of America, Local 12-A v. Nickles Bakery, inc., July 7, 20, 22, 1970 (Box 2, Volume 8-10)
- Second Annual Convention of the Pennsylvania State Board American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union, AFL-CIO, September 15-17, 1959 (Box 2, Volume 11)
- Eighth Annual Convention of the Pennsylvania State Board American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union, AFL-CIO, October 12-13, 1965 (Box 2, Volume 12)
- Ninth Annual Convention of the Pennsylvania State Board American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union, AFL-CIO, October 15-16, 1966 (Box 2, Volume 13)
- Tenth Annual Convention of the Pennsylvania State Board American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union, AFL-CIO, September 14-16, 1967 (Box 2, Volume 14)
- Proposed Agreement of Merger between Bakery and Confectionery Workers' Internation Union of America and the Tobacco Workers International Union, August 16, 1978 (Box 2, Volume 15)